downrightnow.com 2019-07-09

# Privacy Policy - downrightnow

This privacy policy sets out how downrightnow uses and protects any information that you provide when you use this web site. 

downrightnow is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this web site, you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. 

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are in agreement with any changes. 

**If you are a resident of the European Economic Area ("EEA") or Switzerland, please see the "Users in the EEA and Switzerland" section of this Privacy Policy.**

## Definitions

**Non-personal data (NPD)** is information that is in no way personally identifiable. 

**Personal data (PD)** means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person. PD is in many ways the same as Personally Identifiable Information (PII). However, PD is broader in scope and covers more data. 

A **Visitor** is someone who merely browses our website. 

## Information We Collect

Generally, you control the amount and type of information that you provide to us when using our website. Our legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data (PD) is based on consent. 

**What Happens if you Don't Give Us Your Personal Data (PD)?** If you do not provide us with enough PD, we may not be able to provide you with all our services and functionality. However, you can access and use most parts of our website without giving us your PD. 

## We Collect Your PD in the Following Ways

**Automatic Information**. We automatically receive information from your web browser or mobile device. This information includes the name of the website from which you entered our website, if any, as well as the name of the website you'll visit when you leave our website. This information also includes the IP address of your computer/the proxy server you use to access the Internet, your Internet service provider's name, your web browser type, the type of mobile device, your computer operating system, and data about your browsing activity when using our website. We use all this information to analyze trends among our users to help improve our website. 

**When Entering and Using Our Website**. When you enter and use our website and agree to accept cookies, some of these cookies may contain your PD. 

#### Log Files

Like other web sites, downrightnow makes use of server log files. The information inside the log files includes Internet Protocol (IP) address, web browser type, date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks and is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movement around the site, and gather demographic information. 

#### Optional Status Reports

If you choose to submit a status report on downrightnow, we collect the date/time stamp, the service status you indicate, and your Internet Protocol (IP) address. Submitted status reports are recorded in a cookie to help discourage repeat submissions in a 24-hour period. 

#### Optional Contact Form Submissions

If you choose to send us a message using our contact page, we collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address and any other information you choose to provide with your message, such as your name and email address. 

## Our Use of Cookies

Our website uses cookies. A cookie is a small piece of data or a text file that is downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you access certain websites. Cookies may contain text that can be read by the web server that delivered the cookie to you. The text contained in the cookie generally consists of a sequence of letters and numbers that uniquely identifies your computer or mobile device; it may contain other information as well. 

**By agreeing to accept our use of cookies, you are giving us, and third parties we partner with, permission to place, store, and access some or all the cookies described below on your computer.**

**You can manage your cookie preferences by clicking the "Cookie Settings" link at the bottom of this page.**

**Strictly Necessary Cookies**. These cookies are necessary for proper functioning of the website, such as displaying content, responding to your request for services, and other functions. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of cookies. However, if you disable these cookies, you may not be able to access features on our website correctly or at all. This also includes session cookies. These cookies allow websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They may be used for a variety of purposes, such as remembering user interactions as they browse a website. Session cookies also permit users to be recognized as they navigate a website so that any item or page changes they make are remembered from page to page. Session cookies expire after a browser session; thus, they are not stored long term. 

**Performance Cookies**. These cookies collect information about the use of the website, such as pages visited, traffic sources, users' interests, content management, and other website measurements. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site. 

**Functional Cookies**. These cookies enable the website to remember user's choices — such as their language, username, and other personal choices — while using the website. They can also be used to deliver services, such as letting a user make a blog post, listen to the audio, or watch videos on the website.They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services we have added to our pages. 

**Advertising or Targeting Cookies**. These cookies are usually placed and used by advertising companies to develop a profile of your browsing interests and serve advertisements on other websites that are related to your interests. They do not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. You will see less targeted and more irrelevant advertising if you disable these cookies. 

**Social Media Cookies**. These cookies are set by a range of social media services that we have added to the site to enable you to share our content with your friends and networks. They are capable of tracking your browser across other sites and building up a profile of your interests. This may impact the content and messages you see on other websites you visit. If you disable these cookies you may not be able to use or see these sharing tools. 

We may also use cookies for: 

  * Identifying the areas of our website that you have visited
  * Personalizing content that you see on our website
  * Our website analytics
  * Remembering your preferences, settings, and login details
  * Targeted advertising and serving ads relevant to your interests
  * Allowing you to share content with social networks
  * Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of cookies. However, if you disable cookies, you may not be able to access some features on our website correctly or at all.

#### Doubleclick DART cookie

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on downrightnow. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to downrightnow and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include **Google Adsense**. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology which the advertisements and links that appear on downrightnow send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

downrightnow has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. downrightnow's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites. 

By declining marketing/targeting cookies you will also decline the display of embedded ads by the Google AdSense platform on downrightnow. 

**Google Ad and Content Network Privacy notice**. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's past visits to our website. Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visits to our site and/or other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting <http://www.aboutads.info/>

For European users, visit <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>

**Google Analytics Privacy notice**. Our website uses Google Analytics to collect information about the use of our website. Google Analytics collects information from users such as age, gender, interests, demographics, how often they visit our website, what pages they visit, and what other websites they have used before coming to our website. We use the information we get from Google Analytics to analyze traffic, remarket our products and services to users, improve our marketing, advertising, and to improve our website. We have enabled Google Analytics advertising features such as remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit our website, not your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected using Google Analytics with PD. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google also uses specific identifiers to help collect information about the use of our website. 

For more information on how Google collects and processes your data, visit <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>

You can prevent Google Analytics from using your information by opting out at this link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**Google Remarketing**. Why am I seeing ads by Google for products I've viewed? Our website uses a remarketing advertising service. Our remarketing service is provided by Google and other companies that show our ads on websites across the Internet. With remarketing you may see ads for our products you have previously looked at. As an example, suppose you visit a website that sells computers, but you do not buy a computer on your first visit to that website. The website's owner might like to encourage you to revisit his/her site and buy a computer by showing you his/her ads again on other websites that you visit. We use remarketing for similar purposes. For this to happen, Google will read a cookie that is already in your browser, or they place a cookie in your browser when you visit our site or other sites using remarketing. 

You can opt out of Google's use of cookies and remarketing at this link: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en>

You can opt out of Google's personalized advertising by visiting Google's Ad Settings page at this link: <https://adssettings.google.com/>

You can opt out of other third-party interest-based ads using the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page at: <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>

## How Your Information is Used

We use the information we receive from you to: 

  * Provide the services and functionality you have requested from us
  * Personalize and customize our content
  * Make improvements to our website
  * Respond to problems and inquiries

**Communications and Emails**. We will not share personally-identifiable information or contact information you provide to us with any third parties without your consent. In addition, we will not use this information for marketing or promotional purposes without your consent. 

**Sharing Information with Affiliates and Other Third Parties**. We do not sell or rent your PD to third parties for marketing purposes. 

**Legally Required Releases of Information**. We may be legally required to disclose your PD if such disclosure is (a) required by subpoena, law, or other legal processes; (b) necessary to assist law enforcement officials or government enforcement agencies; (c) necessary to investigate violations of or otherwise enforce our Legal Terms; (d) necessary to protect us from legal action or claims from third parties, including you and/or other users or members; or (e) necessary to protect the legal rights, personal/real property, or personal safety of our company, users, employees, and affiliates. 

**Disclosures to Successors**. If our assets are sold or merge in whole or in part with another entity that would become responsible for providing the website to you, we retain the right to transfer your PD to the new entity. The new entity would retain the right to use your PD according to the terms of this privacy notice as well as to any changes to this privacy notice as instituted by the new entity. 

## Retaining and Destroying Your PD

We retain information that we collect from you (including your PD) only for as long as we need it for legal, business, or tax purposes. Your information may be retained in electronic form, paper form, or a combination of both. When your information is no longer needed, we will destroy, delete, or erase it. 

## Do Not Track Settings

Some web browsers have settings that enable you to request that our website not track your movement within our website. Our website does not obey such settings when transmitted to and detected by our website. You can turn off tracking features and other security settings in your browser by referring to your browser's user manual. 

## Links to Other Websites

Our website may contain links to other websites. These websites are not under our control and are not subject to our privacy notice. These websites will likely have their own privacy notices. We have no responsibility for these websites and we provide links to these websites solely for your convenience. You acknowledge that your use of and access to these websites are solely at your risk. It is your responsibility to check the privacy notices of these websites to see how they treat your PD. 

## Users in the EEA and Switzerland

If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, the following information applies with respect to personal data collected through your use of our Services. 

**Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing** : We process personal data consistent with our disclosures in this privacy policy. We process personal data on the following legal bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to provide services and functionality you request; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing the services where those interests do not override your fundamental rights and freedoms related to data privacy. **EEA and Swiss users may review or update your preferences regarding how downrightnow and our third party partners process your personal data at any time by using the "Cookie Settings" link on this page.**

**Transfers** : Personal data we collect may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates or processors maintain facilities. We will ensure that transfers of personal data to a third country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards. 

**Your Rights** : You are entitled to the rights under Chapter III of the EU General Data Protection Regulation or Section 2 of the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection with respect to the processing of your personal data, which include the right to access and rectify and to request erasure of personal data. **To exercise these rights, contact data(at)downrightnow(dot)com and provide as complete a description of your request as possible.**

## Contacting Us About Privacy Matters

If you have any questions about our privacy notice, please contact us at data(at)downrightnow(dot)com. 

Last updated Wed, June 12, 2019 12:00 AM EDT
